长话短说
Start simple.
你知道的都是真的
Start with what you know is true.
我是凯妮丝·艾佛丁 我家住在12区
My name is Katniss Everdeen. My home is District 12.
我曾经被迫参加饥饿游戏 但我逃出来了
I was in the Hunger Games. I escaped.
比德… 他没有逃出来
Peeta… Peeta was left behind.
艾佛丁小姐？
Miss Everdeen?
你不能待在这里
You can't be in here.
我做噩梦了 再给我5分钟就好
I had a nightmare. Just five more minutes.
你需要睡眠 我们可以帮助你入睡的
You need to sleep. We can help you sleep.
再给我5分钟就好
Just five more minutes.
不行
No.
拜托了 我只要5分钟…
No, please, don't. It's just five more…
别碰我 不 不 放开我
Don't touch me! Don't! No! No! Get off of me!
芬尼克
Finnick.
我想回去找比德和乔安娜
I wanted to go back for Peeta and Johanna,
可是我…
but I, uh…
我动不了
I couldn't move.
他们把安妮也抓走了
They have Annie, too. They took her.
她… 呃
She's, uh…
她现在在都城
She's in the Capitol.
我希望她死了
I wish she was dead.
我希望我们所有人都可以死去
I wish they were all dead and we were, too.
《饥饿游戏3： 嘲笑鸟（上）》
艾佛丁小姐
Miss Everdeen.
我是伯格斯上校 第13区的保安队长
Colonel Boggs, District 13's head of security.
我知道你刚出院
I know you've been discharged,
但是科因总统希望先见见你本人
but President Coin's requested to meet with you first.
有新的消息吗？
Is there any news?
我不知道 我只是被指派来护送你
I'm just here to escort you.
我们曾经都以为13区只剩下一片残骸
We were always told there was nothing left of 13.
都城把13区的表面炸成了废墟
Capitol bombed the surface to rubble.
但我们军人 我们学会了生存
But we're military, so we learned to survive down here.
时刻准备 不停训练
Preparing, training.
我们的战争不曾终止
The war never stopped for us.
她在那里
There she is.
我们燃烧的女孩
Our Girl on Fire.
总统阁下 请让我向您介绍嘲笑鸟
Madam President, may I present you with The Mockingjay.
很荣幸见到你
What an honor it is to meet you.
你真是勇敢的女孩
You're a courageous young woman.
我知道 这一定令人很困惑
I know how disorienting this must be.
我完全无法想象你是如何在这残忍的游戏里生存下来的
And I can't imagine what it's like to live through the atrocities of those Games.
凯妮斯
Katniss,
这是 阿尔玛·科因总统
President Alma Coin.
你能来这里太好了
Please know how welcome you are.
我希望你在13区能过得舒服
I hope you'll find some comfort with us.
13区也损失惨重
We've known loss in 13, too.
这是历史性的一刻 就在这桌子前
This is history. Right here at this table.
我很抱歉
I apologize.
我也希望你有更多时间休息 但很不幸的
I wish you had more time to recover, but unfortunately,
但我们没有那个时间
we don't have that luxury.
请坐
Please, have a seat.
你知道最近都发生了些什么吗？
Are you aware of what's happened?
当你将你的弓箭射向天空
When you fired your arrow at the force field
你点燃了整个国家的战火
you electrified the nation.
你让7个区群情激愤 起来反抗都城
There have been riots and uprisings and strikes in seven districts.
我们相信 如果我们能保持这股激情
We believe that if we keep this energy going
我们就可以联合更多区来反抗都城
we can unify the districts against the Capitol.
如果我们不动作 让机会跑掉
But if we don't, if we let it dissipate,
我们恐怕得再等75年了
we could be waiting another 75 years for this opportunity.
13区的人都已经在为了这一战做准备
Everyone in 13 is ready for this.
比德呢？他还活着吗？
What about Peeta? Is he alive?
我不知道 我也希望我知道
I don't know. And I wish that I did.
我无法联络上我在都城的内应了
But there's no way for me to contact my operatives inside the Capitol.
都城阻断了区与区的信号
The Capitol has always suppressed communication between the districts.
但我很了解他们的系统
But I know their system very well.
我负责寻找方法突破
I managed to break through.
而我们还需要一条讯息
All we need now is the perfect message.
凯妮斯 这是我们现在需要的
Katniss, here's what we need to do.
我们要让其他人看到嘲笑鸟还活着
We need to show them that The Mockingjay's alive and well
激励他们起来反抗
and willing to stand up and join this fight.
因为我们需要联合所有区来反抗都城
'Cause we need every district to stand up to this Capitol.
就如同你射向天空那箭
The way you did.
我们要拍摄一段宣传短片
So we're gonna shoot a series of propaganda clips,
采访 我喜欢称它为
propos, I like to call them,
嘲笑鸟计划
on The Mockingjay.
我要它传开
Spreads the word
我们要点燃暴动的战火
that we're gonna stoke the fire of this rebellion.
从嘲笑鸟开始的反抗之火
The fire that The Mockingjay started.
你把他留在哪里了
You left him there.
- 你把比德留在竞技场等死 - 凯妮斯 那里有很多…
- You left Peeta in that arena to die. - Katniss, there are so many…
比德才是该活下来的那一个
Peeta was the one who was supposed to live.
艾佛丁小姐
Miss Everdeen.
革命是每个人的事
This revolution is about everyone.
这是为了大家
It's about all of us.
而我们需要一个发言人
And we need a voice.
那你那个时候就该救比德
Then you should've saved Peeta.
或许你那个时候就应该救他的
Maybe you should have rescued the boy instead.
喔 不
Oh, no.
我知道的 这是没人可以做得比他更好
No, listen to me. No one else can do this but her.
可是她看起来不如你形容得这么好
This is not the girl you described.
显然 我应该和她私下谈谈
Obviously, we need to make it personal.
提醒她真正的敌人是谁
Remind her who the real enemy is.
她知道的 这不是问题
She knows who the enemy is. That's not the issue.
除非她忘记了
Unless she's forgotten.
我们要给她看看
There's explaining and there's showing.
让他看看都城对12区做了什么
Let her see what the Capitol did to 12.
她根本不能处理好 那游戏已经毁了她
She can't handle it. The Games destroyed her.
但这是我们唯一的机会了
This is the only choice you have.
她不会如你所愿的做事 总统阁下
People don't always show up the way you want them to, Madam President.
但愤怒
But that anger,
可以促使反对派起义 这就是我们想要的
that anger-driven defiance, that's what we want.
我们可以换个方向
And we can redirect it.
我们需要联合所有人
We need to unite these people out there
而不是在赛场上自相残杀
that have been doing nothing but killing each other in an arena for years.
我们必须有一个导火索
We have to have a lightning rod.
那他们就会跟随她 她是反抗行动的领路人
They'll follow her. She's the face of the revolution.
让她去明白 让她回家
Let her see it. Let her go home.
送她去吧
Send her.
我不敢相信在发生那些事之后 你有勇气回去
I can't believe you're going through with this.
你可以拒绝的
You can say "no."
我想要亲眼看看
I need to see it for myself.
这边走
This way.
13区检查过了
13 swept everything, top to bottom
你在这里很安全
so you'd be safe.
你确定不需要我跟着吗？
You sure you don't want me to go with you?
我确定
Yeah. I'm sure.
我们会在空中看照你的
We'll have our eyes on you from above.
菲格斯
Figures.
嘿
Hey!
过来
Come on.
你不想看到普里姆吗？
Don't you wanna see Prim?
喔 你真是伤透我的心
There you go. You're breakin' my heart.
嘘
Shh.
爱吉莉雅
Egeria!
我们要纠正几个词汇
We need to fix these lines.
我不会称他们为「反叛军」
I won't say "rebels."
抵抗是徒劳的
These are senseless acts of defiance.
我不会让它看起来合法的
And I won't legitimize them.
我会叫他们「罪犯」
We'll call them "criminals."
嗯
Mmm.
激进份子？
"Radicals."
嗯
Hmm.
否则就坏了我的老规矩了
Otherwise we're breaking my oldest rule.
不要让敌人看到你弱的那一面
Never let them see you bleed.
市民们
Citizens,
今晚我要说所有施惠国统一了
tonight I address all of Panem as one.
自从那些黑暗的日子之后
Since the Dark Days,
施惠国已经过了一段史无前例的和平
Panem has had an unprecedented era of peace.
而这份和平是大家共同努力的结果
It is a peace built upon cooperation.
遵从命令 守法纪
And a respect for law and order.
但在这几周来 一些零星的暴动
In the past weeks, you have heard of sporadic violence
跟着世纪极限赛里的激进份子暴动
following the actions of a few radicals in the Quarter Quell.
那些选择毁灭之路的人
Those who choose this destructive path,
你们都误会了
your actions are based on a misunderstanding
要如何与我们和睦相处
of how we have survived. Together.
要携手合作
It is a contract.
每个区都供给着都城 就像用血供给着心脏
Each district supplies the Capitol. Like blood to a heart.
做为回馈 都城提供秩序 安全
In return, the Capitol provides order and security.
如果有人罢工
To refuse work
就会让我们整个系统陷入危险
is to put the entire system in danger.
都城是施惠国的心脏
The Capitol is the beating heart of Panem.
没有心脏 施惠国将不复存在
Nothing can survive without a heart.
跪在你们面前的不法之徒 使用标识来煽动暴乱
The criminals that kneel before you use symbols for the purpose of sedition.
这就是为什么所有嘲笑鸟的标识 均应予以禁止
Which is why all images of The Mockingjay are now forbidden.
包庇他们的人会被视为叛国
Possessing them will be considered treason.
判死刑
Punishable by death.
正义应该被伸张
Justice shall be served swiftly.
秩序应该被保存
Order shall be restored.
对于那些谁无视和平历史的警告
To those who ignore the warnings of history…
就该付出代价
…prepare to pay the ultimate price.
没事了
It's okay.
我们很好
We're okay.
我们都在
We're all here now.
小宝贝
Buttercup!
我偷偷带进来的
I smuggled him in.
我有拿爸的照片
I got Dad.
也有拿一些你放在厨房的药草
And I got some of your herbs from the kitchen.
他们有规定
They have strict rules.
我不知道他们发现猫会怎么样
I don't know what they'll do if they find him here.
你应该吃点东西
You should try to eat something.
大家好 晚上好
Hello. Good evening.
欢迎施惠国的大家收看
And a big welcome to all in Panem.
我是 凯撒·佛利克曼
I'm Caesar Flickerman.
不管你是谁 或正在做些什么
And whoever you are, whatever it is you're doing,
如果你在工作 放下手头的活
if you're working, put down your work.
如果您在吃饭 那么请停下来吧
If you're having dinner, stop having dinner.
因为我要你们见证今晚这一刻
Because you are going to want to witness this tonight.
我们要揭密世纪极限赛事件的内幕
There has been rampant speculation about what really happened in the Quarter Quell.
已经出现了很多猜测 而要澄清这些事
And here to shed a little light on the subject for us is a very special guest.
我们邀请比德·梅尔拉克
Please welcome Mr. Peeta Mellark.
比德 很多人搞不清发生了什么事
Peeta, a lot of people feel as though they are in the dark.
对 我知道那种感觉
Yeah, I know how they feel.
现在 可以说一说
Now, so set the stage for us.
到底事情是怎么发生的吗？在那争论性的那一晚
Talk us through what really happened on that final and controversial night.
当然 我希望你们先了解 当你置身于游戏中
Well, first off, you have to understand that when you're in the Games
你只会想着一件事 赌一切
you only get one wish. It's very costly.
你还活着
You're alive.
赌生命
It costs your life.
我想这代价不止是生命
I think it costs more than your life.
什么意思？不止是生命
How do you mean? What's more than your life?
杀害无辜的人 这比失去要沉重
I mean to murder innocent people, that costs everything that you are.
没错
Yes.
所以你只能把希望寄托于一件事上
So you hold on to that one wish.
而我所希望的就是凯妮斯活着
And that night my wish was to save Katniss.
没错
Yes.
那天我应该早跑 应该听她的话
I should've just run off with her earlier in the day like she'd wanted.
但你没有
But you didn't.
为什么呢？你太在意比堤的计划了？
Why? Were you caught up in Beetee's plan?
不 我太在意和他们结盟了
No, I was caught up trying to play allies.
但他们分化我们
And then they separated us
我就因此失去了她
and that's when I lost her.
而当那闪电击中大树
And then the lightning hit
整个竞技场的电磁场都毁了
and the whole force field around the arena just blew out.
是的 比德
Yes, but, Peeta,
你知道那是凯妮斯打爆电磁场的吗？
Katniss is the one who blew it out.
不可能
No.
你看过镜头了
You saw the footage.
不 她当时不知道她在做什么
No, she didn't know what she was doing.
我们都不知道
Neither of us knew
这背后还有阴谋 根本没这个想法
there was a bigger plan going on. We had no idea.
- 你们都不知道？- 不知道
- You had no idea? - No.
好吧 比德 但是看起来十分起疑
All right. Well, Peeta, there are many who find this suspicious
- 的确是这样的 - 嗯
- to say the least. - Mmm-hmm.
看起来她也参与了叛乱计划
It seems as though she was part of a rebel plan.
你觉得她会计划自己差点被乔安娜杀死吗？
Do you think it was part of her plan to be almost killed by Johanna?
或者差点被闪电杀死？
Or part of the plan to be paralyzed by lightning?
不 我们没参与叛乱计划 我们不知道事情会变成这么样的
No, we were not part of any rebel plan. We had no idea what was going on.
好吧 我们相信你 谢谢你 比德·梅尔拉克
All right. I believe you, Peeta Mellark. Thank you.
谢谢
Yeah.
我应该要问你对于叛乱份子的看法的
And I was going to ask you to speak about the unrest
但我想你可能太难过了
but I think you might be too upset.
不 我可以
No, I can.
- 你确定吗？- 没错
- Are you sure? - Yeah, absolutely.
谢谢
Thank you.
我希望大家停下来
I want everyone who's watching to stop
想想这些叛乱的后果
and to think about what a civil war could mean.
我们曾经面临过一次
We almost went extinct once before.
现在人口急剧下降
And now our numbers are even fewer.
他是他们的人了
He's one of them.
这是你们希望的吗？
Is this really what we wanna do?
他是个叛徒
He's a traitor.
杀死我们所有人？
Kill ourselves off?
杀戮不能解决问题
Killing is not the answer.
我不敢相信他会这么说
I can't believe he's doing this.
大家应该要马上放下武器
Everyone needs to lay down their weapons immediately.
叛徒
Traitor!
他不是我们的一份子
He's not one of us!
这是叛国罪
This is treason!
你是在呼吁大家停火吗？
Are you calling for a ceasefire?
没错
Yeah. I am.
你是一个傀儡
You're a puppet!
吊死他
Hang him!
我希望大家停止无意义的暴力行为
I want everyone to stop the senseless violence.
这不是一条对的路
This is not the path to change.
叛徒
Traitor!
这不是条正义的道路
It's not the path to justice.
不可能有任何停火
There can't be a ceasefire.
尤其是看到诺斯的暴行后
Not after everything Snow's done.
今晚比德的话造成了很多不良影响
He could have done a lot of damage tonight.
很多区的人 还不敢挺身反抗
Most districts, people are still too afraid to join.
他们需要勇气
They need the courage.
你觉得他为什么会这样说？
Why do you think he said that?
我不知道 或许他是被强迫的
I don't know. Maybe he was forced.
但他看起来好好的
He didn't look that bad.
或许他为了保护你 而达成的交易
Maybe he made some kind of deal to protect you.
他还身陷游戏之中无法自拔
He's still playing the game.
不 不 不
No! No! No!
我很抱歉 我刚做了恶梦
I'm sorry. It's just a nightmare.
没关系 我也经常这样
That's okay. I get 'em, too.
比德
Peeta,
你可以陪陪我吗？
will you stay with me?
可以
Yeah.
我永远都可以
Always.
嘿
Hey.
睡不着？
Can't sleep?
跟我说说怎么了吧
Tell me what's happening.
我很善于保守秘密的
I'm good at keeping secrets.
对妈妈也是
Even from Mom.
没有人比我更讨厌都城
No one hates the Capitol more than me.
我想帮忙 但我总想…
And I wanna help. But I just keep thinking,
就算赢了 比德怎么办？
even if we win this war, what happens to Peeta?
他在那里不安全 在这里也是
I know he's not safe there, but he's definitely not safe here.
我想你不了解 你对其他人来说也多重要
I don't think you know how important you are to them.
如果你想要什么 你可以开口和他们谈
If you want something, you just have to ask.
你几乎可以要求任何事
You could demand almost anything.
他们都会答应的
They'd have to agree to it.
我应该多和你聊天的 小丫头
I should wake you up more often, Little Duck.
睡觉把吧
Get some sleep now.
你也是
You, too.
谢谢你们见我
Thank you for agreeing to meet with me.
我决定要帮助你们
I've decided I'll be your Mockingjay.
但是我有几个条件
But I have some conditions.
比德和其他参赛者 乔安娜·梅森 安妮·克莱斯塔
Peeta and the other Tributes, Johanna Mason and Annie Cresta,
他们应当在第一时间获救
will be rescued at the earliest opportunity.
如果比德被解救
If and when Peeta is liberated,
他的罪刑无条件赦免
he will receive a full and unconditional pardon.
他不会受到任何惩罚
No punishment will be inflicted.
其他参与者也同样
And the same goes for the other Tributes.
不行
No.
他们没有错 是你把他们留在竞技场的
It's not their fault you abandoned them in the arena.
他们会这样说只是为了生存
They're doing and saying whatever they can to survive.
13区不允许有个人的要求
Individuals don't make demands in 13.
会有一场公正的审判的
There will be a tribunal. And a fair judgment.
谢谢你
Thank you.
胜利者应当有豁免权才对
The Victors will be granted immunity.
你必须在13区所有人面前宣布他们无罪
And you will announce that in front of the entire population of 13.
你要用你的权力来完成这件事
You will hold yourself and your government responsible
要不然你就找另一只嘲笑鸟吧
or you will find another Mockingjay.
有没有 我就说了 就是这样
That's it. That's her. Right there.
我不是跟你保证过了
Isn't that who I promised you?
当她穿上戏服
She wears the costume.
背景弄上炮火 硝烟滚滚
Gunfire in the background. A hint of smoke.
这就是我们要的嘲笑鸟
Our Mockingjay.
总统阁下 我们遭受了挫折 因为人人看不到信心
Madam President, we're losing ground, because the people are losing heart.
这值得冒这个险
This is worth the risk.
她是值得的
She's worth the risk.
赦免他们 法庭 人民权利
Pardons, tribunals. Power of the people.
这是打造新的施惠国所需要的
It can all be the bedrock of the new Panem, but,
为了这一件 我想可以做一点小小的让步 对吧？
in wartime I think even the noblest of causes can be bent a little bit. Right?
你还有别的要求吗？
Do you have any other conditions?
我妹妹可以养猫
My sister gets to keep her cat.
走开
Go away.
现在又是探访时间了？
Is it visiting hours again?
特林奇小姐
Miss Trinket,
你看到了
you see this door.
这个门也是可以从里面打开的
It opens. From the inside.
我告诉过你 这是这里生活的人 人人平等
I've told you, these are the standard living quarters. Same as everyone.
你不是犯人 在13区您可以自由的活动
You're not a prisoner. You're free to join the rest of 13.
我感觉不到这样 但还是谢谢你
Not looking like this. Thank you very much.
我们还有比衣服更大的问题吗 特林奇小姐
We have a bigger issue than wardrobe, Miss Trinket.
凯妮斯答应成为嘲笑鸟
Katniss has agreed to be The Mockingjay.
可怜的凯妮斯
That poor thing.
燃烧的女孩已经快筋疲力尽了
And your Girl on Fire is burnt out.
我需要你加入我们
I need you to join this team now.
我需要有他信任的人
I need someone she trusts.
黑密契呢？
What about Haymitch?
他还在下面一英里的地方隔离着
He's drying out in some facility a mile down.
帮助反叛者并不是我的强项
Aiding rebels is not really my forte.
特林奇小姐 不管这里将发生什么
Miss Trinket, your days in the Capitol are over,
你在都城的日子都结束了
no matter what happens here.
如果你想要当个战犯 可以
If you wanna play a prisoner of war, fine.
就留在这里等死吧
Stay here and rot.
我会找到其他人的成为嘲笑鸟的陪护者
I'll find someone else to be The Mockingjay's escort.
谁？
Who?
人人都可以被取代
Anyone can be replaced.
但嘲笑鸟只有一个
Not your Mockingjay.
这里没有人比我了解凯妮斯
There isn't a soul in this dungeon who knows the first thing about Katniss.
你真的认为这里的穴居人
You honestly believe one of these cave dwellers
可以取代我？
is going to take my place?
不
No.
下午好
Good afternoon.
很抱歉 打扰了各位的安排
Thank you for interrupting your schedules.
他们已经进行了调整 以补偿各位…
They have already been adjusted to compensate for the delay.
我几乎没看过有小孩子在这里出现
I hardly ever see children around here.
请检查你们的…
Please, check in with your unit supervisors when you resume work.
很多小孩死于几年前的瘟疫
A lot of them were lost in an epidemic a few years ago.
我有事情要对13区的人宣布
I have an announcement for the citizens of 13.
科因那时也失去了亲人
Coin lost her family, too.
女儿和丈夫
Daughter and a husband.
我们12区的嘉宾
And our welcome guests from 12.
凯妮斯·艾佛丁已经决定要帮助我们反抗
Katniss Everdeen has consented to be the face of our cause
帮助我们联合其他区 反抗都城
to help unite the districts against the Capitol.
为了达成协议 我同意了几个要求
In exchange, I have promised several concessions.
首先 我们会先抢救在都城里
First, we'll assess all opportunities for the extraction of the Victors
那些被挟持住的参赛者
held hostage in the Capitol.
比德·梅尔拉克
Peeta Mellark…
乔安娜·梅森
Johanna Mason…
芬妮克 我也跟安妮谈好了
Finnick, I made the deal for Annie, too.
还有安妮·克莱斯塔
…and Annie Cresta.
一旦成功救出
Once freed,
他们所有的罪刑将被赦免
they will be granted full pardon for any and all crimes
赦免他对我们的伤害
committed against the rebel cause.
很好
Good.
太好了 凯妮斯
That's good, Katniss.
如果凯妮斯·艾佛丁没有办法达成她的承诺
If Katniss Everdeen fails to fulfill her duties
交易就不再算数
the deal will be off.
谢谢你们的聆听
Thank you for your attention.
请继续你的日常生活
Please, resume your daily schedules.
总统阁下
Madam President.
埃菲·特林奇
Effie Trinket.
欢迎来到13区
Welcome to 13.
总统阁下 我可以说你真是…
Madam President, may I say you are so very
- 简明扼要 - 嗯
- concise. - Mmm.
你觉得我还要补充什么吗？
You believe that there's more to be said?
我可以坦率地说吗？
May I speak freely?
没见你说任何事情
You don't appear to do anything else.
我想谈我们的说服力
I'm only talking about salesmanship.
所谓的革命应 往往是星星之火
The thing with revolutions, they're a tender flame.
要加入热情和热情来煽动
They need to be nurtured with a little kindling and warmth.
也要氧气
Bit of oxygen.
氧气
Oxygen.
平淡如水只会熄灭火种
One sure way to put it out is to smother it.
话多也会耗尽屋内氧气的
Or to use up all the air in the room.
借过
Excuse me.
你知道什么东西可以帮助革命吗？发型
You know what could use a revolution? That hair.
埃菲？
Effie?
哦
Oh!
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我现在是个政治难民
I'm a political refugee.
普鲁塔克救你出来的？
Plutarch rescued you?
救我？对 他自己是这样说的
Rescued, yes, that's what he calls it.
现在你和我都眼前一抹黑
You and I were both in the dark.
我要抱怨一下这种穿囚服的烂生活了
Now I'm condemned to this life of jumpsuits.
能见到你真好
It is wonderful to see you again.
你相信这里吗？
Can you believe this place?
我想念我的咖啡
I miss coffee.
我没想过竟然会有一个地方这么严格
I never knew anyplace could be so strict.
我以为我这种高解除人会有些…
I mean, I thought at least in the higher ranks there'd be some
特别待遇
side action.
我想死我的假发了
I miss my wigs.
还好 我记得这个发型
Luckily, I remembered that this was all the rage
当初也是很流行的
when I was coming up.
你知道的 流行有时会重复
You know, everything old can be made new again.
就像是民主
Like democracy.
这是我来的原因
Which brings me to this.
西纳
Cinna.
他死了 对吧？
He's dead, isn't he?
是的
Yes, dear.
他答应普鲁塔克不告诉你这个…
He made Plutarch promise not to show you this
除非你自愿答应我们成为嘲笑鸟
until you'd decided to be The Mockingjay on your own.
他知道风险很大 我们也知道
He knew the risks. As we all do.
他相信这场革命
He believed in this revolution.
他相信你
He believed in you.
它们真美
They're beautiful.
他们做好了
They have it.
他们都有嘲笑鸟的服装
They have the Mockingjay outfit.
在13区这里没有大的筹备组
There's not much of a prep team here in 13
但我们会让你
but we will make you
成为史上最漂亮的反叛者的
the best-dressed rebel in history.
好的
Okay.
灯光准备
Bring up the lights.
西纳的遗作
Cinna's final touch.
送给世界上所有的想要亲吻你的 杀你的
Everyone's either gonna wanna kiss you, kill you,
或是你
or be you.
完美
Perfect.
非常完美
Absolutely perfect.
打开背景
Okay. Let's bring up the setting.
嗯
Huh.
一点点风
Little Wind.
好的 凯妮斯 我们需要你以跪姿出场
Okay, Katniss, we're gonna start you down on one knee.
- 好 - 当你起身时
- Okay. - And as you rise up,
要挥舞旗帜 说出你的台词
you're gonna hold your flag in the air and deliver your line.
记得你刚和都城打完一丈
And remember you've just stormed the outskirts of the Capitol
和你的兄弟姊妹一起奋斗完
arm-in-arm with your brothers and sisters.
好的
Okay.
等你准备好就可以开始了
Whenever you're ready.
施惠国的各位 我们…
People of Panem, we fight, we dare, we…
她知道台词吗？
Does she know the line?
- 我知道 我记得 抱歉 - 好的 没关系
- I know it. I got it. I'm sorry. - Okay, All right.
- 再来一次吧 - 她是在热身
- Let's do it again. - She's warming up.
好 激情一点 开始
All right. With energy. Go.
施惠国的各位
People of Panem, we fight!
我们应当勇敢反抗这种不义的行为
We dare to end this hunger for justice!
你才刚打完仗
You've just been in battle!
抱歉 我忘了我的情绪
I'm sorry. Excuse my outburst.
但你要记住你刚打完一场仗
You've just been in battle.
我们再来一次
Let's try it again.
等你准备好
Whenever you're ready.
施惠国的各位 我们反抗
People of Panem, we fight!
勇敢的反抗这些不义的行为
We dare to end this hunger for justice.
我的朋友 这就是革命失败的开始
And that, my friends, is how a revolution dies.
你好 凯妮斯
Hello, Katniss.
你是这样招呼老朋友的？
This how you greet an old friend?
也许是我认不出清醒的你
Maybe I don't recognize you sober.
我想一定很糟吧
I guess it looks as bad as it feels.
施惠国的各位 我们反抗
People of Panem, we fight!
勇敢的反抗这些不义的行为
We dare! We end this hunger for justice!
总统阁下
Uh, Madam President,
请让我稍微放纵一下吧
indulge me for a moment, if you would.
让我们想想
Let's everybody think of one incident
凯妮斯·艾佛丁曾经在什么时候使你们感动过
where Katniss Everdeen genuinely moved you.
不是让他们去羡慕她的发型
Not where you were jealous of her hairstyle
也不是她的燃烧的衣服
or her dress went up in flames
也不是她向天空射了一箭
or she made a halfway decent shot with an arrow.
也不是和比德的爱
And not where Peeta made you like her.
不 我希望你们能想起一个时刻
No, I'd like you all to think of one moment
- 要让她感觉到真实的东西 - 哦
- where she made you feel something real. - Oh.
在收割日 她为了她妹妹而自愿参加比赛
When she volunteered for her sister at the Reaping.
这是一个非常好的例子
Excellent example.
好的
Okay.
我希望这不是重要的
I hope that wasn't important.
呃 好的 「自愿替妹妹上场」
Uh… Okay, "Volunteer for sister."
好的 还有吗？
Good. What else?
当她为鲁唱歌时
Oh. When she sang that song for little Rue.
没错 谁不被打动呢？
Oh, yeah. Who didn't get choked up at that?
你知道吗 埃菲 我喜欢没装扮的你
You know, I like you better, Effie, without all that makeup.
我比较喜欢清醒的你
Well, I like you better sober.
当她和鲁成为盟友的时候
When she chose Rue as an ally, as well.
嗯 没错
Mmm, yes.
所有这些有什么共同之处？
Now, what do all these have in common?
没有人告诉她这样做
No one told her what to do.
没有剧本 对吧
Unscripted, yes.
所以 或许我们只须要让她独自一个
So maybe we should just leave her alone.
洗掉化妆吧
And wash her face.
她只是个女孩 你把他搞得像35岁的大妈
She's still a girl. You made her look 35.
真情流露的机会很少
The opportunities for spontaneity are obviously
在地下避难所
lacking below ground.
所以你要我们让她去作战？
So what you're suggesting is we toss her into combat?
我不能让没有受过训练的平民出现在战场
I can't sanction putting an untrained civilian
战争只是为了增加效果
in battle just for effect.
这不是都成
This is not the Capitol.
其实我认为只要将她放在战场就可以了
That is exactly what I'm suggesting. Put her in the field.
不 我们无法保护他的安全
No, we can't protect her.
但这是必要的
It has to come from her.
这是人民需要的
That's what people respond to.
你需要一个革命的象征
You want a symbol for the revolution?
我们不能强迫她表现出任何我们要的感情
She cannot be coached into it. Trust me, I know.
或许我们就应该找些 比较不这么危险的地方
Maybe there's someplace that's less dangerous.
第8区 他们上礼拜才被轰炸而已
District 8. They reported heavy bombing last week.
已没任何军事目标了
There are no military targets left.
我们没有办法保证他的安全
We can't guarantee her safety.
你永远无法保证我的安全
You'll never be able to guarantee my safety.
我要去
I wanna go.
如果你死了呢？
And if you're killed?
那希望你有拍到那一幕
Make sure you get it on camera.
我有为你做了些惊喜
I've made you some surprises.
或许你会想要试试看
Maybe you wanna try one out.
如果你要加入凯妮斯的队伍
If you're gonna be a part of Katniss' propo team,
就要有一定的水准
you may as well look the part.
这是给你的
And this one is for you.
普鲁塔克希望你有
Plutarch wanted you to have a weapon
属于自己的武器
for the sake of the propos
但我实在做不出来很时髦的来
but I couldn't just make you a fashion accessory.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
来看看这个
And look here.
常规的 燃烧的 爆裂的三种弓箭
Regular. Incendiary. Explosive arrows.
都用颜色标记了
All color-coded.
还有 帮我跟芬尼克说
And tell Finnick
我也有为他准备三叉戟
I've got a trident for him
如果他准备好了
when he's ready.
尽量… 鼓励他一下吧
Might just cheer him… Cheer him up.
呃
Uh…
这里不可以使用红色的那种
Let's not fire the red ones in here.
你们有这么多武器 却让其他的区孤军奋斗？
You had all of this and you just left the districts to fend for themselves?
凯妮斯 没这么简单 我们勉强撑了下来
It's not that simple, Katniss. We barely survived.
但我们没有办法反击
We weren't in any kind of shape to launch a counterattack.
没错 我们可以轰炸都城
Yeah, we could've bombed the Capitol
但他们至少会轰炸我们两次作为反击
but they would've retaliated with at least twice the firepower.
然后呢？
Then what?
即便胜利了 也无人存活
There would've been nobody left to claim victory.
听起来就跟比德说的一样 但你们还说他是叛徒
Sounds like exactly what Peeta said and then you all called him a traitor.
这边请 士兵
This way, soldier.
你真上镜
You are camera-ready.
你不觉得他很帅吗？
Doesn't your comrade look handsome?
我们走吧
Let's go.
平安归来
Come back safe.
简单介绍一下 凯妮斯
Quick introductions, Katniss.
他们都是远道而来参与这个计划的人
These people have come a long way to support the cause.
这是 克瑞西达
This is Cressida.
我记忆中在都城里最棒的导演
In my opinion one of the best up-and-coming directors in the Capitol.
当然是直到我离开之前啦
Until I up and left. Hey.
嘿
Hey…
让我们看看你能做些什么吧
Let's see what you can do.
好吧 小心
All right. Be careful.
这是我的助手梅撒拉
This is my assistant, Messalla.
很高兴认识你
It's an honor to meet you.
摄影师 卡斯特
And your cameramen over there, Castor.
你好
Hello.
还有波勒克斯
And Pollux.
系好安全带吧
Let's get locked in.
你们都来自都城吗？
You're all from the Capitol?
普鲁塔克去救你们出来的？
Plutarch got you out?
别期望他跟你聊天了
Don't expect much chitchat from him.
他没有办法说话 几年前他被都城切去了舌头
He's an Avox. Capitol cut his tongue out years ago.
还有 没有你所谓的「救」出来
And, no, it wasn't any sort of rescue, if that's what you mean.
我们所有人都出逃了
We all fled on our own.
因为
For this.
为了你
For you.
动作要快 速战速决
This has gotta be fast. In and out.
行动
Move out.
你还活着 我们都不确定呢
You're alive then. We weren't sure.
凯妮斯 这是第8区的指挥官 佩勒
Katniss, Commander Paylor, District 8.
凯妮斯还在康复期间 但她坚持
Katniss has been recovering, but she insisted on coming out
探望受伤的人
and seein' some of your wounded.
我们有很多伤员
Well, we've got plenty of those.
我们在那里有一个万人坑 但 我没有多余的人力可以清理
We have a mass grave a few blocks west, but, I can't spare the manpower to move them yet.
医院在幕布后面
Hospital's past that curtain.
希望你可以给他们希望
Any hope you can give them, it's worth it.
都城为了消灭我们无所不为
The Capitol's done everything they can to break us.
你不担心你的伤员都在同一个建筑物里吗？
Aren't you worried about having all your wounded in one place?
我想这样总比让他们自己等死好
I think it's better than leaving them to die.
我不是这个意思
That's not what I meant.
这其实也是我们唯一的选择了
Well, that's my only other option.
如果你有其它的办法 我也愿意听看看
You can come up with another, I'm all ears.
穿过去就到了
It's right through here.
不要在这里拍 我帮不了他们
Don't film me in there. I can't help them.
就让他们看到你的脸就可以了
Just let them see your face.
借过
Excuse me.
嗯 你还好吗？
Yeah. You all right?
好了 没事了
It's okay. Here, it's okay.
我抓到你了 都没事了
I've got you. It's all right.
凯妮斯·艾佛丁？
Katniss Everdeen?
你怎么会在这里？
What are you doing here?
我来看你们
I came to see you.
你的孩子呢？
What about the baby?
我流产了
I lost it.
你还在反抗吗 凯妮斯？
Are you fighting, Katniss?
你是来和我们一起反抗的吗？
You here to fight with us?
是的
I am.
我会的
I will.
靠近些
Tighter.
再靠近一点
Tighter, tighter.
有些监控摄像头在轰炸之后损坏了
Sir, some cameras were damaged in the bombings,
但我们确定就是她
but we confirmed it's her.
缩小
Zoom in.
她那时正在前往一个临时医院
She was visiting a makeshift hospital.
我们不确定她现在还在不在
We're not sure if she's still there.
嗯
Hmm.
我们可以从11区派飞船去消灭他们
We can scramble hovercraft from the border of 11.
我们可以锁定她了
We may be able to target her.
嗯
Hmm.
杀光那些伤员
Kill the wounded.
长官…
Sir…
你自己帮我写演讲稿吧 爱吉莉雅
You wrote that speech yourself, Egeria.
任何有关嘲笑鸟的标识都是被禁止的
Any association with the Mockingjay symbol is forbidden.
医院里的所有人都违反了
Everyone inside that hospital has committed treason.
让他们看看与凯妮斯·艾佛丁为伍的代价吧
Show them what it costs to be friends with Katniss Everdeen.
等你妈看到视频 他会为你骄傲的
Your mom's gonna be proud of you when she sees the footage.
他们会在每个区播放吗？
Will this play in the districts?
当然 会让他们印象深刻的
It'll be tattooed on their eyes.
有情况
There's a problem.
怎么回事？
What kinda problem?
有轰炸机从北边袭来
Incoming bombers from the north.
我们得找掩护
We need to find cover now.
那里有遮蔽物
There's a bunker in there.
直走到底下楼梯
Straight ahead and down the stairs.
凯妮斯
Katniss!
艾佛丁 艾佛丁
Everdeen! Everdeen!
盖尔 离墙远一点
Gale, back away from the wall!
你还好吗？
You okay?
快跑
Move!
他们追着什么东西去了南边
They're going after something to the south.
他们朝医院去了
That's towards the hospital.
他们要掉头回来了 来吧
They're circling back around. Come on!
医院
That's the hospital.
他们的目标是医院
They're targeting the hospital.
帮帮他们
Help them!
帮帮他们逃出来
Help them! Get them out!
凯妮斯？
Katniss?
你可以告诉大家你现在看到什么吗？
Katniss, can you tell everyone what you're seeing right now?
你想说什么？
Katniss, what do you wanna say?
我想让所有反叛者知道我还活着
I want the rebels to know that I'm alive.
我现在在第8区
That I'm in District 8
都城刚刚轰炸了这里的医院
where the Capitol just bombed a hospital
里面手无寸铁的伤员 女人和小孩
filled with unarmed men, women and children.
无人幸存下来
And there will be no survivors.
如果你以为都城会公平的对待我们
If you think for one second that the Capitol will ever treat us fairly
那就是你在自欺欺人罢了
you are lying to yourselves.
因为我们知道他们是怎么样的人
Because we know who they are and what they do.
这就是他们会做的事 我们一定要反抗
This is what they do! And we must fight back.
我有一段话要给斯诺
I have a message for President Snow.
你可以折磨我们 轰炸我们的区
You can torture us and bomb us and burn our districts to the ground.
但你看到了吗？
But do you see that?
火焰已被点燃
Fire is catching.
如果我们身处火海 那你也会葬身火海
And if we burn, you burn with us!
因为我们知道他们是怎么样的人
We know who they are and what they do.
这就是他们会做的事
This is what they do!
我们一定要反抗
And we must fight back.
你可以折磨我们
You can torture us and bomb us
轰炸我们的区
and burn our districts to the ground.
普鲁塔克对你的信任没错
Plutarch's faith in you wasn't misplaced.
但你看到了吗？
But do you see that?
谢谢
Thank you.
火焰已被点燃
Fire is catching.
和我一起奋斗吧
Come up with me for the beginning.
如果我们身处火海 那你也会葬身火海
And if we burn, you burn with us!
没有妥协就没有进步
There is no progress without compromise.
没有牺牲就没有胜利
No victory without sacrifice.
我如今我和嘲笑鸟站在这里
But I stand here with The Mockingjay
宣布 我们的时代已经到来
to announce that our moment has arrived.
比堤已经把我们的广播讯号提高了10倍传输
Beetee has increased our use of the airwaves tenfold.
我们今晚会将这段视频
We will broadcast this message
在各个区播放
to all the districts tonight.
嘲笑鸟的话
The Mockingjay's words
会激励所有人起来反抗
inspiring everyone to join the rebellion.
团结一致 我们将会是坚不可摧的联盟
Together, we will become an alliance to be reckoned with.
必胜 必胜 必胜
Hoorah! Hoorah! Hoorah!
我知道你不希望有这么多人参战
You don't like hearing a fight song at a funeral, huh?
但我们的人越多 比德和安妮就更有希望
The more people on our side, the closer we are to Peeta and Annie.
是的
Yeah.
斯诺总统下令
By order of President Snow
日产量已增加
daily production quotas have been increased.
所有工作班次将会增加两个小时
All work shifts will be extended by an extra two hours.
没做完不能休息
Failure to meet these quotas will not be tolerated.
斯诺总统下令 日产量已增加
By order of President Snow daily production quotas have been increased.
如果我们身处火海 那你也会葬身火海
If we burn, you burn with us!
- 我有新的消息 - 什么消息？
- I got good news. - What?
科因同意让我们去地面打猎
Coin agreed to let us hunt above ground.
他甚至不害怕我们
He's not even afraid of us.
那是因为他们没有被猎捕过
It's 'cause they've never been hunted before.
这很不公平
It's almost not fair.
他们要我们回去了
They want us back.
他们要我们去大厅
They asked us to head for Command.
好 但先让我放一下东西
All right. I gotta drop these off.
她可以说是我们最好的贡品
She was arguably our favorite Tribute.
但我想最令人惊讶的
And I think that's what we all find most astonishing,
就是那女孩 曾经深受都城人民的爱戴
is that this girl was adored in the Capitol.
让我想起你 比德
And I think for you, Peeta,
我知道这一定很痛苦
it must be particularly painful.
我希望我可以把这些玫瑰给你 凯妮斯
I wish I could give this rose to you, Katniss.
他变了好多 他们对他做了什么？
He's changed so much already. What are they doing to him?
一份贴心的礼物 送给一个燃起战火的女孩
A sweet gesture for a girl who has inspired such violence.
你一定很爱她 所以你才会原谅她
You must love her very much to be able to forgive her.
你是在颤抖吗？
He's shaking.
是的 我忍不住
I don't think that I could.
当然 比德 会不会凯妮斯是…
Unless, of course, Peeta, you think that perhaps she's being
被迫说出
forced into saying
一些她甚至都不明白的事？
things that she doesn't even understand.
我就是这么想的
Yeah. That's exactly what I think.
连声音都不对
Even his voice is different.
我想他们是要用这招击溃反叛军
I think they're using her to whip up the rebels.
我怀疑你知道这是
I doubt she even knows what's happening.
怎么回事
And what's really at stake.
比德 我想叛军不会让她看这个的
Now, Peeta, I doubt that the rebels will ever let her see this.
但如果她看到了 你想和她说什么？
But if they do, what would you say to her?
给你最爱的凯妮斯·艾佛丁
To Katniss Everdeen, the once sweet Katniss Everdeen.
我会告诉她… 多为自己想想
I would tell her to think for herself.
好的
Yes.
别傻了 凯妮斯
Don't be a fool, Katniss.
我知道你不希望反抗的
I know you never wanted the rebellion.
游戏中你做的那些 绝不是有意要反叛的
The things that you did in the Games were never intended to start all of this.
反叛军把你搞得不像你了
The rebels have made you into something that you're not.
把你搞成毁灭我们的机器
Something that could destroy all of us.
如果你还有能力
So if you have any power or any say
可以拒绝他们利用你 或者撼动他们的决议
in what they do or how they use you,
我请求 请求 要他们停止战争
please, please, urge them to stop this war
在一切都来不及之前停下来
before it's too late.
然后问问你自己
And ask yourself,
你能相信现在和你共事的人吗？
can you trust the people you're working with?
你确定你知道他们真正要的是什么吗？
Do you know what they really want?
我们必须作出回应
We need to respond.
谢谢你 比德·梅尔拉克
Thank you, Peeta Mellark, for these
和我们分享这段和嘲笑鸟有关的访问
revelations about the real Mockingjay.
你看到他怎么了吗？
Did you see what he looks like?
我看到一个懦夫
I saw a coward.
你不知道他都遭受过了什么
You don't have any idea what he's going through.
我才不在乎 我都不会说出他刚刚说的那种话
I don't care. I would never say what he just said.
不管是不是有一把枪顶着我的头
Not if they tortured me. Not with a gun to my head.
这和当初帮助你躲避鞭刑的比德是同一个人
That is the same Peeta that defended you at the whipping post.
不 已经不是了 现在他只会为了自己做事
No, it's not. Now he's only defending himself.
总统要我们去开会 我们要做出回应
Coin's called a meeting. We need to respond.
什么时候你和总统变成「你们」了
When did "we" become you and Coin?
每个人都有选择
Everyone has a choice.
他怎么可以坐在都城帮助那些
How can he sit there in the Capitol and defend the people
毁了他的家园的人呢？
who destroyed his home and murdered his family?
他不知道啊
He doesn't know.
他怎么可能知道
How could he?
没有人知道都城对12区做了什么
Nobody's seen what the Capitol did to 12.
我们得让他们知道
I have to show them.
我希望我们从正义楼开始拍摄 可以吗？
So I wanna start with you in front of the Justice Building, okay?
第一幕
Bang. First shot.
凯妮斯 告诉我们这里怎么了
Katniss, tell us what happened here.
我们曾经都站在这里
We were all standin' right here
看你在游戏中向天空射出那一箭
watchin' the Games when you fired that arrow.
突然间荧幕黑了
The screens just went dark.
没有人知道怎么一回事
Nobody had any idea what happened.
治安官要我们各自回家
Peacekeepers forced us back into our homes.
一个小时之后整个城镇一片死寂
For maybe an hour, the town was just dead quiet.
9点后 我们看到卡车都撤出了
Little past 9:00, we heard their trucks pullin' out.
每个治安官都离开了
All of them. Every single Peacekeeper.
我们知道这代表什么
And I knew what that meant.
我和矿场里的几个朋友
Me and a couple of guys from the mines,
开始把大家拉出来
we started pulling people from their houses
希望可以逃出轰炸
and tried to get 'em to the fence line
但有些人害怕夜晚的森林
but a lotta people were scared of the forest.
他们转向大路去了
So they headed up onto the road.
或许就是那里
Make a break for it that way.
跟着他
Stay with Gale.
915个人逃到了栅栏那边
915 of us made it to the fence.
然后 轰炸机到了大路那边
Then we watched as bombers circled back towards the road.
他们把他们炸死了
They firebombed them as they ran away.
1万人中只有915个活下来
915 outta 10, 000.
我应该拉着他们跟我走的
I should've grabbed people. I should've dragged 'em with me.
我还可多带几个小孩的
Some of the kids I could've carried.
你已经救了很多人了 盖尔
You saved so many people, Gale.
没有你 就没有12区
Without you, there would be no District 12.
甚至回忆也没了
Not even the memory of it.
这是你吻我的地方
This is where you kissed me.
我想你应该不记得
I didn't think you remembered that.
除非我死 才会忘记
I'd have to be dead to forget that.
或许死也不会忘记
Maybe not even then.
我知道你会那么做
I knew you'd do that.
为什么你知道？
How? I didn't.
因为我很痛苦
'Cause I'm in pain.
这是我引起你的注意的唯一办法了
That's the only way that I can get your attention.
别担心 这些都会过去的
Don't worry, Katniss. It'll pass.
嘿
Hey…
那里有一只嘲笑鸟
Yeah, that's a mockingjay.
他们现在会叫个不停
Well, now they'll never shut up.
你想唱首歌吗？
You want me to sing?
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
男子吊死之处
Where they strung up a man
谣传三人为他所诛
They say who murdered three
吊诡之事接连而出
Strange things did happen here
诡异无比
No stranger would it be
但当我们午夜相会于此吊人树
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
死去的人呼唤着他的爱人 一起私奔
Where a dead man called out for his love to flee
吊诡之事接连而出
Strange things did happen here
诡异无比
No stranger would it be
但当我们午夜相会于此吊人树
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
告诉过你要逃离
Where I told you to run so we'd both be free
唯此你我才能自由
So we'd both be free
吊诡之事接连而出
Strange things did happen here
诡异无比
No stranger would it be
但当我们午夜相会于此吊人树
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
于此吊人树
In the hanging tree.
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
戴上希望的锁链 与我吊在一起
Wear a necklace of hope side by side with me
原本的歌词是「绳做的项链」
That line was originally "necklace of rope."
我把它改成「希望的项链」了
I had it changed to "necklace of hope."
哇 你真是厉害
Wow. You are a true wordsmith.
小意思 当然 战争就是这样
Little on the nose, but, of course, so is war.
所有区域都看的到这个吗？
Every district's seeing this?
除了都城以外都可以
Yes. But not the Capitol.
当初是我为他们设计这套防御系统的
I designed this signal defense system for them.
结果我自己竟然不会破解
But I can't find my way through it.
我想是我把我的工作做得太完美了
Guess I did my job too well.
那个时候 当时我满脑子是科学研究
At the time, I was just thinking of the science of it all.
我们可以黑进去的
We'll get through it.
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
男子吊死之处谣传三人为他所诛
Where they strung up a man they say who murdered three
吊诡之事接连而出
Strange things did happen here
诡异无比
No stranger would it be
但当我们午夜相会于此吊人树
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
是否 是否 来此树下
Are you, are you comin' to the tree?
死去的人呼唤着他的爱人 一起私奔
Where a dead man called out for his love to flee
吊诡之事接连而出
Strange things did happen here
诡异无比
No stranger would it be
但当我们午夜相会于此吊人树
If we met at midnight in the hanging tree
前进 还有反向前进
Moves and countermoves.
凯妮斯 总统在控制室要见你
Katniss, you're wanted in Command.
我们收到报告
Tonight, we've received reports
今晚有火车出轨
of derailed trains,
粮仓被烧
of granaries on fire,
还有人攻击了第5区的发电所
and of a savage attack on the hydroelectric dam in District 5.
他们对你了什么？
Oh, what have they done to you?
我一直呼吁理性和平
I'm begging for restraint and decency.
我们入侵他们的信号了
We interrupt your regularly scheduled horse manure
这样就可以…
to bring you…
来此树下
Comin' to the tree?
就是这样 我们的视频
That's it. That's our footage.
比堤进去了
Beetee's in.
谣传三人为他所诛
They say who murdered three
凯妮斯？
Katniss?
他看到了 他看到了
He sees it. He sees our propo.
诡异无比
No stranger would it be…
凯妮斯 是你吗？
Katniss, are you there?
比德
Peeta.
凯妮斯？
Katniss?
比德 请继续
Peeta, please continue.
我们刚谈到那些野蛮的袭击
You were telling us about these savage attacks.
对
Yeah.
那些在发电所的冲突是冷酷
The attack on the dam was a callous
不人道的破坏性行为
and inhuman act of destruction…
死去的人呼唤着他的爱人 一起私奔
Where a dead man called out for his love to flee
试想
Think about it.
这会如何结束 结束之后又能剩下些什么？
How will this end? What Will be left?
没有可以活下来
No one can survive this.
没有人是安全的
No one is safe now.
在都城也是
Not here in the Capitol.
在任何区也没有人是安全的
Not in any of the districts.
凯妮斯 他们来了
They're coming, Katniss.
他们要杀光13区所有人
They're gonna kill everyone.
明天早上13区将会惨不忍睹
And in District 13 you'll be dead by morning.
他在警告我们
He's warning us. That was a warning.
对 是的
Yes, it was.
你得在他们杀了他之前救他出来
We have to get him out before they kill him.
目前空中有什么威胁吗？
Is there anything in the air?
雷达上没有目标
Nothing on Doppler, ma'am.
他一直都在都城 或许可以偷听到些什么
He was in the mansion. He could have overheard something.
有可能
Possibly.
是时候空袭演习了
It's time for an air raid drill.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静
Please, remain calm
开始疏散
and begin evacuation protocol.
普里姆 普里姆
Prim! Prim!
尽速到达你最近的避难区 并下至40层
Proceed to your nearest stairwell and descend to level 40.
安全门将会在6分钟后关闭
Blast doors will be sealed in six minutes.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静 开始疏散
Please, remain calm and begin evacuation protocol.
请有秩序的到达你最近的避难区
Proceed in an orderly fashion to your nearest stairwell
并下至40层
and descend to level 40.
总统阁下
Madam President,
都城的三个中队刚刚入侵了我们的领空
three Capitol squadrons just entered our airspace.
我们还有多久时间？
How much time do we have?
只剩下几秒了进入射程
They're a few seconds from range.
准备好舰队
Prepare to scramble the fleet.
收到
Copy that.
打开所有防御系统
Open up short-range air defense.
准备远程导弹反击
Arm long-range missiles for counterattack.
安全门将会在5分钟后关闭
Blast doors will be sealed in five minutes.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静 开始疏散
Please, remain calm and begin evacuation protocol.
请有秩序的到达你最近的避难区
Proceed in an orderly fashion to your nearest stairwell
并下至40层
and descend to level 40.
安全门将会在4分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in four minutes.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
请保持冷静 开始疏散
Please, remain calm and begin evacuation protocol.
请有秩序的到达你最近的避难区
Proceed in an orderly fashion to your nearest stairwell
并下至40层
and descend to level 40.
安全门将会在3分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in three minutes.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
请有秩序的到达你最近的避难区
Proceed in an orderly fashion to your nearest stairwell
并下至40层
and descend to level 40.
请尽速去供应站提领物资
Continue to the Supply Station and claim one pack
每个成员都要拿到
for each member of your compartment.
请将所有个人物品放置在自己的区域
Please keep all personal items within your assigned area.
礼让同胞
Be courteous to your fellow citizens.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
所有人应当到避难所避难
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
- 安全门2分钟后关闭 - 妈
- Blast doors will close in two minutes. - Mom!
普里姆在哪？
Where's Prim?
我以为她去找你了
I thought she went to find you.
她一定还在楼梯
She must still be on the stairs.
楼梯上没有人了
There's no one on the stairs.
他回去找猫了
She went back for the cat.
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
所有人应当到避难所避难
All citizens should be inside the bunker.
嘿 站住 站住
Hey, stop! Stop!
安全门将在1分钟后关闭
Blast doors will close in one minute.
他们轰炸了西北部四分之一地区
They hit the far edge of the northwest quadrant.
穿透地下12米
Penetrated 40 feet.
没有击中居住区域
Missed the living quarters.
只有第2 3走廊受损
Only minor damage to corridors 2 and 3.
有辐射外泄吗？
Is there any radiation?
没有侦测到
None detected.
雷达显示第4波攻击到达了
Doppler shows a fourth wave approaching.
安全门将在30秒后关闭
Blast doors will close in 30 seconds.
普里姆
Prim!
凯妮斯
Katniss!
这是红色警报
This is a code red alert.
凯妮斯
Katniss!
安全门将在15秒后关闭
Blast doors will close in 15 seconds.
快下来
Get down here!
- 快 - 这是红色警报
- Hurry! - This is a code red alert.
安全门将在10秒后关闭
Blast doors will close in 10 seconds.
Nine…
Eight…
Seven…
Six…
- 5 - 别关门
- Five… - Hold the doors!
Four…
Three…
- 2 - 等等 先别关门
- Two… - Wait! Hold the doors!
One.
你跑回去找猫？你到底在想什么？
You went back for the cat? What were you thinking?
我不能把它留下
I wasn't gonna leave him behind.
没有它我活不了
I couldn't live with myself.
安全门已封闭
Blast doors are now sealed.
我知道了 普里姆
I know, Prim.
我们走吧
Let's go.
已经攻击到西北部的含水层了
Damage to the aquifer in the northwest quadrant.
我们已经失去至少一个交通走廊了
We lost a transport corridor.
西北区将再也没有东西了
There's nothing else in the northwest.
我们地对空的武器刚刚
Our surface-to-air launchers just took
雷达3区被攻击了
a direct hit in sector 3.
因为我们暴露自己了
Because we revealed ourselves.
他们发现了我们开火位置
They saw us firing there.
取消 不启动舰队
Stand down. Don't launch the fleet.
又有都城12架轰炸机到了 第3区已经被锁定了
Another 12 Capitol bombers approaching sector 3 in attack formation.
让他们接近不要开火
Hold fire on their approach.
哦
Oh.
他们击中了什么？
What'd they hit?
一块岩石 有杂物在通风管道中
Bedrock. But there's debris in the ventilation shaft.
他们不知道我们的设备位置
They're not targeting our fleet.
也不清楚我们特殊武器
Or our Special Weaponry.
他们不知道我们有什么 或者放在何处
They don't know what we have or where we have it.
你可以确定所有人都已经到达避难所了吗？
Can you confirm that everyone's safely in the bunker?
是的
Already done.
隐藏所有其他防空炮
Conceal all remaining anti-aircraft guns.
关闭发射平台和通风走廊
Seal launching pads and ventilation corridors.
我们要度过这一切
We are gonna wait this out.
这就是我们在地下的原因
This is what we're built for.
我们锁定了这里就像一座坟墓
They'll seal us in here like a tomb.
都成没有任何最新的信息
The Capitol's working off some outdated information.
我不想帮他们更新资讯
I'd rather not update it for them.
总统阁下 这不是我的…
Madam President, I know it's not my place…
没错 你是贵宾 但不要管的太深
It's not. You're a welcome guest, but you're out of your depth down here.
减少14％的氧气 用于长期供应
Reduce oxygen to 14% to conserve it.
收到
Copy that…
深呼吸 黑文斯比先生
Take a deep breath, Mr. Heavensbee.
这会是漫长的一晚啊
It's gonna be a long night.
普里姆 跟我说说什么事吧 说什么都可以
Prim, talk about something. Anything.
他们要提拔我去医院帮忙
They promoted me at the hospital.
我忘记告诉你了
I forgot to tell you.
他们要训练我当医生
They're training me to be a doctor.
他们不这么做才是白痴
They'd be stupid not to.
嘿
Hey…
我可坐下吗？
Can I sit?
可以
Yeah.
斯诺用安妮逞罚你
Snow's using Annie to punish you.
用他们来嘲笑我们
He's taunting us with them.
我一直不懂 直到我刚刚看到了那只蠢猫抓影子
I didn't understand until just now watching that stupid cat.
在你第一场饥饿游戏之后
After your first Games,
我以为那场恋爱只是演戏罢了
I thought the whole romance was an act.
我们都希望你继续这样演下去
We all expected you to continue that strategy.
但当比德心脏停止时 快要死掉时
But it wasn't until Peeta's heart stopped and he nearly died that
我知道我看错你了
I knew I'd misjudged you.
你深爱他
You love him.
事实就是如此
I'm not saying in what way.
或许你自己也不知道
Maybe you don't even know yourself.
但任何有在专心看的人都看得出来
But anyone paying attention can see it.
你整么撑过来的？
How do you live with it?
我整晚噩梦侵袭 无法解脱
I drag myself outta nightmares and there's no relief in waking up.
但 不要自暴自弃
But it's better not to give in to it.
你得振作起来 比起让自己崩溃
Takes 10 times longer to put yourself back together
要难上10倍
than it does to fall apart.
凯妮斯 凯妮斯？
Katniss? Katniss?
跟我们走
Come with me.
我们撑过了他们的攻击 不是吗？
We took their best shot. Didn't we?
是的
Yeah.
你家人还好吗？
Your mother and sister okay?
嗯 还好
Yeah, they're fine.
我需要你帮我们做一件事
I need you to do something for us.
我们要告诉施惠国的所有人 我们撑住了
I need you to tell Panem that we survived an attack by the Capitol
而且完好无损
with no casualties.
我们仍然可以全面运作
And we remain fully operational.
好的
Okay.
你有件事情必须要知道
You should know something.
我们多了8分钟 可以撤离民众
We had eight extra minutes of civilian evacuation
都是因为比德的警告
because of Peeta's warning.
我不会忘记的
I won't forget that.
谢谢你
Thank you.
所以 凯妮斯
So Katniss,
「13区完好无损 我也一样」
it's "13 is alive and well and so am I."
凯妮斯
Katniss?
Katniss.
我知道没有人喜欢排练
Never one to waste it in rehearsal, I know.
他们为什么扔下这些？
Why would they drop these?
是针对我的
For me.
准备好了吗 凯妮斯？
Ready to go, Katniss?
我们得像在第8区那样 开始拍摄
We're gonna do this, just like District 8.
告诉我有关玫瑰的事情
Tell me about the roses.
告诉斯诺 13区完好无损 我也一样
Tell Snow 13 is alive and well.
他会杀了比德的
He's gonna kill Peeta.
我们再来一次 你得说大声一点
Let's try again. Can you speak up?
我们没给你麦克风
We don't have a mic on you.
「13区完好无损 我也一样」
"13 is alive and well and so am l."
他会杀了比德的
He's gonna kill Peeta.
我做不到
I can't.
凯妮斯？
Katniss?
你可以的 凯妮斯
You can do it, Katniss.
不 我不行
I can't do this.
「13区完好无损 我也一样」
"13 is alive and well and so am l."
他会继续…
He's just gonna keep…
他不会停止
He's never gonna stop.
克瑞西达 先停止吧
Cressida, we should cut the cameras.
- 只要我还是嘲笑鸟 - 没事的 凯妮斯
- …as long as I'm The Mockingjay. - It's okay, Katniss.
不 他警告我了 提醒我这件事
No. He warned me. He warned me about this.
他这么做是因为我是嘲笑鸟
He's doing this because I'm The Mockingjay.
他用惩罚比德来惩罚我
He's punishing Peeta to punish me.
不
No.
不 我做不到
No, I can't do this.
凯妮斯
Katniss.
别逼我
Don't make me do this!
让她去吧
Let her go.
我要离开这里
I gotta get out of here.
所以 就这样结束？
So this is the end, huh?
你是想永远躲在这下面吗？
I s'pose you're just gonna hide down here forever?
我不能再当嘲笑鸟了
I can't be The Mockingjay.
你不当嘲笑鸟 当凯妮斯就够了
Not The Mockingjay. Just Katniss.
你知道 你是我在这下面唯一的朋友
You know, you're the only real friend I have down here.
我可不希望他们给你下药
I don't suppose they gave you any kind of medication?
你根本不可靠
You're unbelievable.
好吧 但我说的是真的
Okay, but I meant what I said.
听着 我在这里就是让你知道
Look, the reason I'm here is to let you know
他们也在救比德
they're rescuing Peeta.
什么？
What?
第5区的电厂坏了 断绝了给都城的大部分电力
The dam went down in District 5, took out most of the power to the Capitol.
防御系统失效了
Knocked out their signal defense.
比堤正在对系统进行破坏
Beetee's inside their system now, wreaking all kinds of havoc.
我们找到一个漏洞
A window is open to us.
但我不知道他能维持多久
How much longer? I don't know.
大概等都城回复电力就不行了
I guess until the Capitol can get the power back on.
总统科因？
And President Coin?
我想我不会永远支持这个女人
You know, I can never fully support that woman
因为她这里有禁酒令…
in light of the prohibition they have going on around this place,
但… 普鲁塔克收到情报
but Plutarch got word
比德和其他人都被关在贡品中心
that Peeta and the others are in the Tribute Center.
加上电力消失 总统认为这是一个机会
And with the power out, Coin sees this as an opportunity.
她知道比德
She knows that Peeta
就是都城的武器 就像你是我们的一样
is the Capitol's weapon. The same way you're ours.
你们对对方都具有影响力
And as opposed to having you two pointing at each other,
她要去救他
she's going to get him.
我必须去帮忙
I have to go help.
嘿 嘿 孩子 等等
Hey, hey, whoa, kiddo. Wait.
得了吧 干什么 你不会想要直接跑去都城
Come on. What, are you just gonna jump outta the vent
送死吧？
and go storm the Capitol?
除此之外 行动已经开始了
Besides, it's already underway.
6个士兵志愿去了
Six soldiers went in. Volunteer only.
猜猜谁是第一个勇敢报名的
And guess who was the first brave soul to sign up.
盖尔
Gale.
- 好的 芬尼克？- 对 对
- Okay, Finnick? - Yeah. Yeah.
站到中间 站到石头上面
Go in the center there. Those rocks.
卡斯特 去左边
Castor, to left.
波勒克斯 过来
Pollux, you're with me.
那我们直接对着镜头
So we'll go straight to camera.
好了吗 芬尼克？
Okay? Finnick?
好了
Yeah.
好的
Okay.
抓紧时间
Take your time.
记得要一直说话 不要停下来
Just remember to keep talking and don't stop.
我是芬尼克·奥迪尔
This is Finnick Odair.
第65届饥饿游戏的胜利者
Winner of the 65th Hunger Games.
我要告诉你 13区活下来了
And I'm coming to you from District 13, alive and well.
我们撑过都城的攻击了
We've survived an assault from the Capitol.
但我不是来给你报导最新的新闻的
But I'm not here to give you recent news.
为什么芬尼克在录影？
Why is Finnick doing a propo?
我要告诉你们更多
It's a lot more than that.
比堤控制了系统
Beetee's commandeered the system.
他们现在用的发电机功率不够
Now that they're down to generator power
他们没有这么高的频率控制系统
there's a more limited range of frequencies available to them.
我们要用芬尼克的视频占用全部的信号
And I'm filling them all up with Finnick.
虽然不会有很多人会看到它
Not many will see it, but whoever does
但他们相信这是另一个短片
will think it's another propo.
他们不知道的是
What they don't know is this broadcast
他们的传输系统已完全被干扰
is jamming their entire system with noise.
他的早期预警 内部通信 搞趴下所有的一切
Early defense warning, internal communications, everything.
只要视频继续播放
As long as the broadcast goes through,
我们的营救小组 就可以神不知鬼不觉的出入
our team should be able to get in and out undetected.
真相不是奢华生活的神话
The truth. Not the myths about a life of luxury.
不是荣耀祖国的谎言
Not the lie about glory for your homeland.
你可以在竞技场活下来
You can survive the arena.
在你存活下来的那一刻 你就是永远的奴隶
The moment you leave, you're a slave.
嘲笑鸟1 嘲笑鸟1
Mockingjay One, Mockingjay One,
你们还有1分钟进入敌方外线防线
you are one minute out from perimeter defense.
关灯
Going dark.
启用低空飞行系统 保持连线
Stay low in case they're online.
斯诺总统曾经出售我的精神
President Snow used to sell me.
我的肉体 至少 我不是唯一一个
Or my body, at least. I wasn't the only one.
如果胜利者者被认为是招人喜欢
If a Victor is considered desirable,
总统把它作为奖励 出售他们
the President gives them as a reward or allows people to buy them.
如果拒绝 他就杀死你心爱的人
If you refuse, he kills someone you love.
嘲笑鸟1 你们还有20秒进入敌方外线防线
Mockingjay One, you are 20 seconds from perimeter defense.
Ten seconds.
9 8
Nine… Eight…
7 6 5
Seven… Six… Five…
4 3 2
Four… Three… Two…
One.
外线防线没有反应
No response from perimeter defense.
我们进入都城领空
We're inside Capitol airspace.
为了减轻愧疚
To make themselves feel better,
我的主顾会给我钱或珠宝
my patrons would make presents of money or jewelry.
但我发现了比这都还重要的东西
But I found a much more valuable form of payment.
秘密
Secrets.
准备
Gear up.
开启夜视镜
Switching 110 Night View.
那里
There.
指挥官 我们可以看到贡品中心了
Command, we have visual on the Tribute Center.
准备着陆
Initiating final approach.
戴上面罩
Masks on.
我看到的是堕落 谎言和残暴
See, I know all the depravity, the deceit and the cruelty
娇生惯养的都城精英
of the Capitol's pampered elite.
但有个关于科利奥兰纳斯·斯诺总统的大秘密
But the biggest secrets are about our good President, Coriolanus Snow.
打开门
Open the door.
指挥官 我是队长
Command, this is Team Leader.
准备释放气体 我们要确认进去了
Prepare to deploy gas. We will confirm once inside.
如此一个年轻人爬到顶峰
Such a young man when he rose to power.
并聪明地维护权利
Such a clever one to keep it.
你可能会想 他是怎么做到的？
How, you may ask, did he do it?
一个字
One word.
毒
Poison.
准备降落
Get ready to drop.
他每次把叛乱扼杀在摇篮
He stopped every mutiny before it even started.
安全
Clear.
安全 指挥官 我们进来了
Clear. Command, we're inside.
向一号目标前进
Heading toward target number one.
2C下层 P45房间
Cell P45 lower level 2C.
瓦斯
Gas.
有许多反对者神秘的死亡
There are so many mysterious deaths to adversaries.
甚至连盟友都被怀疑
Even to allies who were threats.
斯诺为了避免引起猜疑
Snow would drink from the same cup,
就从同一个毒杯子喝水
to deflect suspicion.
但解毒剂不是都有效
But antidotes don't always work,
他用气味重的玫瑰
which is why he wears roses that reek of perfume.
是为了掩盖他腐烂 满嘴的血腥味
Help cover the scent of blood from sores in his mouth that will never heal.
盖尔
Gale.
但毕竟是无法掩盖他真实的自己
But he can't hide the scent of who he really is.
这个无情的侩子手
He kills without mercy.
用欺骗和恐吓手段统治着人们
He rules with deception and fear.
只有一种武器适合他这种人
His weapon of choice is the only thing suited to such a man.
毒
Poison.
属于蛇的完美武器
The perfect weapon for a snake.
这是哪里？
What is this place?
- 比堤？- 我失去信号了
- Beetee? - I'm losing them.
电力回复了
Powering back up.
都城的防御系统回复了 正在重启
Ma'am, the Capitol air defense system is rebooting. It's coming back online.
他们一定从哪里得到了电力
Must be diverting power from another source.
等待传输
And filtering transmissions.
在60秒后 我们就会被切断信号
Another 60 seconds and we'll be cut off
总统 我们要叫回飞船吗？
Madam President, should we call back the hovercraft?
传送给我
Broadcast me.
如果斯诺在看 他会让信号传输进去
If Snow's watching this, maybe he'll let the signal in,
如果他看到我
if he sees me.
把我传上去吧 让他来见我
Put me on the air so he can see me.
好的 好的
Yes. Yes.
拍他
Put her on.
我们可以做什么 我们可以发送吗？
Can we do this? Can we still get in?
是的 现在还可以
Yes. For the moment.
仅开放见到你的线路
The line's open. He will only see you.
凯妮斯 来吧
Okay, Katniss, go.
斯诺总统？
President Snow?
斯诺总统 我是凯妮斯
President Snow. It's Katniss.
他不一定在看
There's no guarantee he's even watching.
我知道 或许他在
I know, but he might be.
斯诺总统 我有话要对你说
President Snow, I need to speak with you.
你在听吗？
Are you there?
斯诺总统 我是凯妮斯 你听的到我吗？
President Snow, it's Katniss. Can you hear me?
我要跟你说话
I need to speak with you.
斯诺总统 我是凯妮斯
President Snow, it's Katniss.
斯诺总统
President Snow,
你在听吗？
are you there?
在听到我了吗？
Can you hear me?
斯诺总统
President Snow…
艾佛丁小姐 荣幸啊
Miss Everdeen. What an honor.
真不敢想像你要打电话来 谢谢我送你玫瑰
I don't imagine you're calling to thank me for the roses.
我没有说我要
I never asked for this.
我也没有说过我要参加游戏
I never asked to be in the Games.
伯格斯？收到了吗 伯格斯？
Boggs? Come in. Boggs?
我也不曾要求成为嘲笑鸟
I never asked to be The Mockingjay.
我只想要救我妹妹
Just wanted to save my sister.
和比德
And keep Peeta alive.
收到了吗 伯格斯？
Come in. Boggs?
拜托了 放他走
Please, just let him go.
我不会在当嘲笑鸟了
And I will stop being The Mockingjay.
如果你不想见我 我也可以消失的
I will disappear. You will never have to see me ever again.
艾佛丁小姐
Miss Everdeen.
伯格斯 收到了
Boggs, come in.
你无法逃避这些的
You couldn't run from this…
收到
Copy.
就像你永远无法从游戏中逃脱
…any more than you could have run from the Games.
指挥官 我需要知道目前的情况
Command, I need a situation report.
伯格斯 我们快要没有时间了 快点
Boggs, we're running out of time. Hurry.
我们走
Let's move.
求你了
Please.
你已经赢了
You've won.
你已经打倒我了
You've already beaten me.
放走比德吧 由我代替他
Release Peeta. And take me instead.
我不会给你
We're long past the opportunity
牺牲的机会
for noble sacrifice
那你告诉我该怎么做
Then tell me what to do.
我不是一直都谨守诺言吗？
I've always kept my promises, haven't I?
你说你不想要有战争
You said you didn't want a war.
但它还是发生了
And that's just what's happened.
我已经告诉过你「和平」是多么脆弱的东西
I told you what a fragile thing peace was.
而你 还是像个孩子 你乐于打破和平
And still, like a child, you took pleasure in breaking it.
我知道你是怎样一个人
I know what you are.
我知道你会目光短浅 做事任性
I know you can't see past your narrowest concerns.
但 艾佛丁小姐
But please, Miss Everdeen.
我怀疑你知不知道「诚实」是什么意思
I doubt you know what honesty is anymore.
我们到第一目标这里了
Command, we're at the first target.
准备营救比德
Preparing to extract Peeta.
我们要确定一下他是否还在
Will confirm when he's in hand.
嘲笑鸟1 准备飞船撤离
Mockingjay One, prepare hovercraft for evac.
你要我说服你我爱比德
You asked me to convince you that I was in love with Peeta.
我最后还不是做到了？
Haven't I at least done that?
艾佛丁小姐
Miss Everdeen,
那些我们最爱的
it's the things we love most
往往会毁了我们
that destroy us.
我希望你记得我说过这句话
I want you to remember that I said that.
你怎么会以为我不知道你朋友在贡品中心？
Don't you think I know your friends are in the Tribute Center?
关掉他们
Cut them off.
- 怎么了？- 伯格斯 请回话
- What happened? - Boggs, come in.
怎么了？
What happened?
伯格斯 请回话 你听的到我说话吗？
Boggs, come in. Do you read me?
他知道他们在那里
He knows that they're in there.
- 这是陷阱 - 凯妮斯 坚持住
- It's a trap. - Katniss, hold it.
我们要帮他们
We have to get a hold of them.
要告诉他们 斯诺知道了
We have to tell them to get out. He knows.
没有信号了 我们连络不到他们
There's no signal. We can't contact them.
不 黑密契 他一直知道 他故意要折磨我的
No. Haymitch, he knew the whole time. He was taunting me.
不 黑密契 他知道他们在那里
No, Haymitch. They're in there.
我们还不确定
No, we don't know that.
我今晚就要失去他们两个了？
Did I lose them both tonight?
- 我今晚就要失去他们两个了？- 嘘嘘
- Did I lose them both tonight? - Shh.
我今晚就要失去他们两个了？
Did I lose them? I lost them both.
不 不
No! No!
没有消息
There's no news.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
这是这世界最煎熬的事情
It's the worst torture in the world.
等待 因为你知道自己无能为力
Waiting, when you know there's nothing you can do.
尤其是像我们这样的人
Especially for people like us.
但不管是坚强 勇气
But whatever strength, courage,
还是疯狂
madness,
会让我们继续前进 尤其在这样的时刻
keeps us going, you find it, at times like these.
你可以的 士兵
You have it, soldier.
这都是让你活到现在的动力
It's what's kept you alive all this time.
而且它永远打不倒你
And it won't fail you now.
他们回来了
They're back.
我不要那个
I don't want that.
乔安娜
Johanna.
芬尼克
Finnick!
安妮？
Annie? Annie!
你安全了 你安全了…
You're safe. You're safe.
盖尔
Gale!
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
怎么了？发生什么了？
What? What is it?
我不懂
I don't get it.
所有的武器都联机
Every gun was back online
对着我们 而我们却飞过他们的防线
and on us and we flew right past them.
他们放了我们
They let us go.
他在里面
He's in there.
我们的警卫用了瓦斯
Gas we used on the guards
也把他弄昏了 但他现在醒来了
knocked him out, too, but it's wearing off now.
他醒来时 你应该要在
You should be there when he wakes up.
谢谢你
Thank you.
比德
Peeta.
Peeta!
比德 放开她
Peeta! Get off! Get off of her!
走开
Let go!
不 凯妮斯 你脖子肿起来了 别动
No, Katniss. No, you're swollen. Don't touch.
不 冷静下来
No, no, no. Calm down.
冷静下来 你没事了
Calm down. You're okay.
告诉她她醒了
Tell her she's awake.
先别说话
Don't try to talk.
比德很好 我保证
Peeta's okay. I promise.
我只是要把他先和你隔离开
I just had to get him off you.
这叫做「劫持」
It's called hijacking.
我不知道都城对他用药多久了
We don't know how long the Capitol's been doing this to Peeta.
这是对于恐惧的条件反射
It's fear conditioning.
这与杀人毒蜂的介入有关
Enhanced with tracker jacker venom.
你在第一场饥饿游戏中被咬伤时 记得吗？
You were stung your first Games. Remember?
毒物会使人处于虚幻状态
The venom puts the subject in a dissociative state.
然后他们虐待他
And they torture him.
他们用电击和殴打折磨他 直到摧毁他的精神意志
With shocks and beatings, and strip down his identity.
然后把所有的痛苦和恐惧重新组合
And then all of that suffering and fear is redirected.
变成有着别的记忆的一个人
Associated with other memories or a person.
他们可以改变他对凯妮斯的记忆？
They can change his memories of Katniss?
为了看起来像她是一个致命的威胁
To make her seem life-threatening.
他们把他变成了武器 凯妮斯
They turned him into a weapon, Katniss.
来杀你
To kill you.
但你可以解决吧？
But you can reverse it?
恐惧是最难以克服的
The fear is the most difficult thing to overcome.
心中记得的恐惧比什么都重要
We're hardwired to remember fear best.
这是新的领域
It's new terrain.
但我们已经有新的团队在研究了
But we've put together a team.
情况很乐观的
I'm optimistic.
晚上好
Good evening.
昨天 我授权了
Yesterday, I authorized
一个在都城内的救援行动
a covert rescue mission inside the Capitol.
我很高兴得宣布
I am pleased to announce
所有的胜利者都已经获救了
that the Victors have been liberated!
让这一天赋上了新的历史意义
Let this day mark an historic change.
有了嘲笑鸟和胜利者们
With The Mockingjay and the Victors beside us,
我们已经对都城发出了一段明确的讯息
we have sent a clear message to the Capitol.
那就是我们将不再忍受他们的不公正的待遇
That we will never again endure injustice.
今天
Today,
我们就像一个大家庭团聚在一起
a day on which we reunited family,
朋友和亲人
friends, and loved ones.
让施惠国的大家一起团结起来
Let all of Panem come together.
不再为了娱乐都城而战斗
Not to battle for the amusement of the Capitol.
要齐心协力 肩并肩反抗
But to join hands in this fight.
让今天成为我们再次承诺的见证
Let today be the day we promise
永不放弃 永不投降
never to give up, never to give in
直到我们打造新的施惠国
until we have made a new Panem,
一个民选领导者 不再强加思想
where leaders are elected, not imposed upon us.
各区可以自由
And where the districts are free
分享他们的劳动成果…
to share the fruits of their labors
和平共处互助互利
and not fight one another for scraps!
新的施惠国就在前方
This new Panem is on the horizon.
但我要靠自己努力才行
But we must take it for ourselves.
在通往崎岖蜿蜒的山路
The road there leads through the sharp mountains
在深藏地底的第２区
and deep ravines of District 2.
那就是施惠国的心脏地带
There in the heart of Panem's steepest mountain range lies
有着都城所有的军事武力
the Capitol's principal military facility.
我们可以直夺大本营
We can conquer this stronghold
因为我们是同一个人
because we are one people,
同一支军队 有同一个声音
one army, one voice.
因为今天是一个崭新的开始
Because today is our new beginning.
今天我们解放了所有胜利者
Today we have freed the Victors.
明天 就是施惠国
Tomorrow, Panem!
必胜 必胜 必胜
Hoorah! Hoorah! Hoorah!